NETWORK ENGINEER

Summary

Focused Network Engineer Possessing Effective Organizational Skills with experience in configuring and deploying network devices, Security Devices and providing network support for troubleshooting connectivity issues at large and small enterprise environments and having the commitment to keep up to date with latest developments.

Skills

- Cisco Routers, Cisco Switches, Cisco Infrastructure Services: DHCP, DNS, SMTP.FTP,
- ASA, F5 TFTP
- Network and Protocols: TCP/IP, OSI Network Management: SNMP, SSH, Telnet, ICMP VLAN, VTP, Inter-Vlan F5: Load Balancing (LTM), ASM,APM
- routing, STP, RSTP, PVST Tools: Cisco Prime, Wire shark, MS Office, MS
- WAN Technologies: Frame Relay, ISDN, PPP, Visio.
- ATM, MPLS, Channel & Leased lines Operating Systems: Windows 10 / 8.1/7 /Vista/XP,
- Network Securities: NAT/PAT, VPN, Filtering, IOS, UNIX, Linux
- IPSec, ACL Programming: Python
- Routing Protocols: RIP, EIGRP, OSPF, BGP, IPV4, Superb interpersonal skills
- IPv6

Experience

10/2015 to Current

Network Engineer San Diego, CA

- Troubleshoot and maintained all networking devices and infrastructure across the enterprise including switches, routers, and firewalls.
- Responsible for Cisco ASA Firewall configuration, Troubleshooting, Administration, Rule Analysis and Rule Modification.
- Configuring and troubleshooting site-site IPSEC VPN.
- Responsible for firewall migration from cisco to F5.
- Responsible for setting up F5 SSL VPN for customers.
- Documenting the migration process, agency architecture diagrams, firewall documentation using Visio Reviewed logs for all networking devices for unresolved abnormalities and problems.
- Communicated with vendors to resolve network outages and periods of reduced performance.

07/2015 to 10/2015

Network Engineer Star2star Communications i¹/₄ Austin, TX

- Installed, configured, tested and maintained operating systems, application software and system management tools.
- Volunteering configuring Cisco switches 3560 series, catalyst 6500 Series, and routers 2900 series.
- Analyzing and documenting the packet drops in the network using network monitoring tools like SolarWinds, Wireshark.
- Implementing traffic filters on Cisco routers using Standard and Extended Access-lists Configuring routing protocols like RIP, RIPv2, EIGRP, OSPF, and BGP Troubleshoot problem on day-to-day basis.

01/2015 to 05/2015

Graduate Teaching Assistant Ohsu il/4 Monmouth, OR

- Advised students on academic plan and course selection.
- Helped professors and teachers in developing course plans Tutoring the coursework and grading the student assignment, projects.

09/2013 to 05/2014

Network Engineer

 Data Point Info solutions - Hyderabad, INDIA Worked closely with a network engineer, Developed Configuration Review procedures, configured and managed routers and switches Configuring and Troubleshooting OSPF and EIGRP Routing Configuring Cisco ASA Firewall Updated Documentation to provide an efficient transition from one employee to the next.

Education and Training

2015

Master of Science: Information Technology Valparaiso University i1/4 City, State Information Technology 89 Prime Focus on Computer Networks, Java Programming, Information Technology, Risk management, Project management.

2014

Bachelor of Science : Computer Science and engineering Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University $\ddot{\imath}$ City , State , India Computer Science and engineering 5

C language, Java Programming, Computer Networks.

Skills

academic, APM, ASM, agency, ATM, BGP, C language, cisco, Cisco Routers, interpersonal skills, Hardware, Computer Networks, DHCP, Documentation, DNS, EIGRP, firewalls, Firewall, Focus, Frame Relay, FTP, Information Technology, ISDN, Java Programming, LAN, Linux, Access, MS Office, Windows, migration, enterprise, Network Management, network engineer, Network, networking, next, Operating Systems, OSI, OSPF, PPP, Prime, Programming, Project management, Protocols, Python, RIP, Risk management, routers, Routing, SSH, Securities,

SMTP, SNMP, SSL, switches, Cisco Switches,	TCP/IP, Telnet, Troubleshoo	t, Troubleshooting, Tutoring, UNI	X, VPN, Visio, Vista, WAN